Welcome to Xieye Tutorial in Summer
This tutorial is designed to help beginners understand the basics of Marvelous Designer
In this tutorial, we will learn how to make this swimsuit
First, insert your virtual model into the work area
Today we will use Hana as our virtual model
You can insert it into the work area by using Library-Avatar-Hana
In the default settings, you can hold down the mouse key and drag it to rotate the view in the 3D window
Roll the mouse wheel to search for the view
Click the X on the upper right corner of the window to temporarily close it and make the work area window bigger
We will create a basic version of the swimsuit based on the
Go to the 2D tool bar to find the tool group of the created version
We want to select the multidirectional tool, the shortcut key is H
Click the shortcut key to draw a straight line
Click the shortcut key to draw a shape
Press Backspace to return
Click the Ctrl key to draw a curve
Press Shift to draw along the reference line
Press Esc to recreate the entire shape
Now we will draw the joint swimsuit
Start drawing from the neck point in the front
Press Ctrl and click to draw the neck curve
Then click on a certain amount of position above the shoulder to create the shoulder strap
Follow the curve drawn by the shoulder, draw a shoulder line, then press Ctrl to draw a curve below the leaf
We also need to draw some outside when drawing the curve below the leaf
Save the side amount
Then release the Ctrl key and click to draw a straight line
Complete the creation of the rest of the line
Create a straight line as a stop point in the waist here
Convenient for subsequent adjustment and complete the creation of the rest of the line
You can refer to the model's internal body style to draw the rest of the part
Also, please note that the human body is thick
When we create the bottom panel, we need to draw a part more
Just like the shoulder strap, we will make a part that is long
Then refer to the pink straight line to draw the bottom point in the front
Then click on the starting point
Complete as the closed shape, the panel is also created
Now the 3D and 2D windows will appear at the same time
The panel shows the texture surface in the default situation
Currently white pure
We switch to the full transparent surface in the 2D display column
You can see more objectively whether there is a place where the panel overlaps
Then select the copy after the full panel
Then buy the right button next to it
Select mirror pasting
So we have a front and back panel
The back panel and the front panel are similar
But we need to make some adjustments
To make it easier to adjust the panel
We first click on the small scissors to separate the edit panel tool group
We will use the edit panel tool to adjust the point line
To adjust the panel
In the front, we will select the edit panel tool group
In the front middle section, click the right button
Select the align to open edit panel
To maintain the panel's alignment operation
Simplify the workflow
The panel that aligns the panel to open edit
The panel shape on the left and right sides and the panel on the panel
Are all created by symmetrical adjustment
Because the follow-up may adjust the back and middle sections
So we use the adjustment panel tool
Select the back panel
Click the right button and select the align panel
Panel and panel line
And click to place it correctly
We can use the panel line tool group
The panel is molded
The line molding tool is the most commonly used tool in it
All you need to do is click it easily
And it will merge the lines together
When handling the panel line
You need to pay attention to the direction of the panel line
To ensure that the direction of the panel line is corresponding
We have to wait a while to create the panel line
Then go to the 3D window
The virtual model display menu
Listen to the mouse
Click the align button at the bottom
Quickly place the panel around the virtual model
These blue dots are the align points
Select the panel in the 3D window
Click the align button
Quickly place the panel around the virtual model
The parallel panel will be automatically arranged
Please look at the screen in the video
Place the panel
After the panel is arranged
You can more objectively confirm
if the panel line is correct
We create the lining line
Use the line marking tool
Create the lining line
Pay attention to the direction of the line
After looking at the simulation
The clothing will fit the model
At this time you can drag the clothing
Cancellation process
I will Boo Line the strap up and down
There are a lot of creases here.
The creases on the waist are because there is a piece of fabric that cannot match the model's curve,
so it is most important to modify the pattern.
Of course, sometimes creases also have something to do with the virtual model's posture.
If you turn to the side view, you will see that the front and back curves of Hanna are very different.
For the amount of fabric on the waist, we can adjust it with the extension tool.
Since there are no creases on the side of the waist, there are creases here in the back.
In other words, what we mainly need to adjust is the back.
The extension tool can be used to open or close a plate.
At this time, we first click the waist point that does not need to be modified,
then the horizontal moving mouse, and click on the back.
Then click to select the upper part of the back and the moving mouse.
Through the preview, you can see that the extension tool is filling or digging a fan part on the plate.
Now move the mouse and click, because we are going to dig out the excess fan part.
After the simulation application is modified, the plate is more close to the curve.
The plate here is a little too narrow.
Let's adjust it with the edit plate tool.
You can adjust it according to your needs with the edit plate tool or the edit circle.
Adjust the plate to cover the underwear part of the model as much as possible.
Open the simulation and drag the plate to straighten the clothes a little.
Then you can adjust the plate according to your needs.
For example, the plate in front is a little narrow, let's manually adjust it again.
Then you can use the edit curve tool to edit the cross-sectional curve.
Please refer to the 3D window, click on the curve, add a curve point, and then adjust the curve.
What we want to do is to make the front and back curves pass together very naturally,
and do not have particularly obvious angles.
Because Hana's chest is relatively plump, there is a little hollow in the lower part of the body.
We want to adjust the curve of the plate in the lower part of the body to fit the body.
Before we modify it, we can use the elastic to do the tightening effect.
Press the Shift key to select the lower curve and the neck curve,
then go to the property editor and select the elastic.
The default ratio is 80%, we will modify it to 95%.
This way, the ratio of our shrinkage will not be too exaggerated.
In real life, these two parts sometimes have a loosening belt or a sticker,
to tighten these positions and make the swimsuit more attached.
Then we will continue to use the edit curve tool to adjust these curves.
The curve of the lower curve in the front is too big, we want to make the curve more natural and soft,
and the connection between the front and back pieces is also handled smoothly.
After initial modification, turn on the simulation to see the effect after modification.
The shoulder strap is now too close to the inside,
we use the edit curve tool to drag it out according to the pink guide line along the curve.
Then you can adjust the curve of the side according to your needs.
Now we turn to the side view, we will see that the side seam line is crooked.
This is because Hana's chest and waist are too big, and the clothes are relatively tight overall.
The solution is to move the side of the chest to the outside to increase the chest circumference.
After opening the simulation, you will see that the situation is a little better.
Next, let's deal with the problem of the opening too close to the bottom.
Move the neck point to adjust the depth of the opening,
if the curve is not smooth, you can manually adjust the curve point.
Try to make these connected sewing lines or curves on both sides of the symmetry
can be smoothly connected together.
We have adjusted the shoulder strap in the front before,
now the shoulder strap in the back also needs to be handled.
Now the whole back looks like a field uniform,
we need to adjust it to look more like a swimsuit.
First, we need to move the shoulder strap along the original curve to the outside,
because now the belt is too close to the inside.
Use the edit curve tool to move the whole shoulder line,
then use the edit curve point tool to adjust the curve curve to be smaller,
try to make it smooth.
After adjustment, open the simulation to check the effect.
After adjusting the shoulder curve, we need to start adjusting the back and center.
If you use the edit curve tool,
directly dragging the back point will affect the back and center curve.
In order not to affect the overall curve curve,
we need to press the first button during the process of dragging the straight line point.
When you press the first button to drag the straight line point,
you will find that the curve is maintained as much as possible.
After dragging to the appropriate position, loosen the mouse,
then use the edit curve tool to manually adjust the back curve.
In the 3D window, select the pattern and you will see that
the back, shoulder and neck curves are adjusted.
However, the sharp corners on the inside are too obvious,
we can adjust the pattern.
You can adjust it according to your actual situation,
try to avoid having a special shape in the seam allowance.
Here, you will see that the shoulder line is particularly close to the front,
so I need to lengthen the shoulder strap on the front and shorten the shoulder strap on the back.
On the shoulder strap on the back,
apply elasticity to make the effect of sticking and tightening,
then you can continue to adjust the pattern according to your needs.
Now let's look at the shoulder strap part,
some are slanted downwards, so modify the shoulder strap on the back.
Now the shoulder strap is a bit too high,
we can move the forward point down a bit.
Now we have completed the basic swimsuit that matches the HANA body shape.
Next, we will adjust the basic swimsuit,
add some additional design.
First, we can change the hair of the built-in model.
Click on the reset button in the lower right corner,
you can reset the interface to the default position
and open the window.
Go to the Elegant Stylized Hair folder,
you can see that the hair of the built-in model is the same as that of the built-in model.
Please note that the hairstyle and shoes of the built-in model
are all virtual models that correspond to each other,
so they can't be used together.
Now the waist has an obvious twist,
we can optimize it through the originator curve tool.
Find the originator curve tool in the edit menu.
Then click on the point on the side to drag,
you will see that the waist line becomes a more circular curve,
such a curve is more natural than the previous straight line.
Adjust the front and back pieces.
Open the model and apply the changes,
you can drag the board to check the balance of the board.
We can also print the board to check the balance.
The printed board will change to orange,
the whole is still very close to the model curve,
so we can save this file,
and then proceed to the next step.
Go to the file store,
store the current file in the right place
and name it.
Now we will create some asymmetric designs and color division on the board.
Start from the back,
use the built-in multidirectional line tool
to create a reference line on the board to cut and tie.
We want to do an asymmetric design,
here I choose to do a cut design on the left,
click on the starting point,
double click to complete the end position of the inner line.
Since there is a symmetrical relationship,
the inner line will be created on both boards at the same time.
In order to follow the asymmetric operation,
we need to remove the symmetrical relationship,
use the adjustment board tool,
select the front and back boards at the same time,
single click to remove the interlocking.
Now the symmetry of the front is opened,
the edge line has disappeared,
and there is no more blue symmetrical line on the back board.
The front is also operated in the same way.
Start from the front to the lower position,
create an inner line.
This line is the cut line on our front.
Use the edit board tool
to select the inner line on the front and back boards,
single click to select the cut line,
select the cut line on the front and back boards,
and then select the cut line.
After cutting the board,
the print effect will be automatically removed.
Select the excess boards,
press the right button to delete them.
Since I want the cut line to be a straight line,
we need to select these excess lines,
and then delete them.
After deleting the lines,
the elasticity applied on the lines will disappear.
We need to re-apply the elasticity manually,
and set the elasticity ratio to 95%.
Now the shoulder strap has been processed.
We are going to start making the cut on the board.
We can make the cut on the board in the 2D window,
or we can also make the cut on the board in the 3D window.
As long as you use the 3D drawing tool,
you can complete the 3D drawing tool set.
These tools will allow you to make the cut on the 3D costume
or on the virtual model freely.
Select the 3D version of the cut line tool.
The operation method of this tool is similar to the 2D drawing line.
Click on the costume to make the cut line.
Press the Shift key to create the cut line along the horizontal vertical direction.
Click on the cut line along the horizontal line.
Click on the starting point again to complete the cut line of a whole circle.
If you want to make a normal cut line,
you can easily create the cut line by holding up the same mouse button.
Press Ctrl Z to return to the starting point.
Press Esc to return to the previous cut.
A whole circle of lines is completed here.
You will see that the 3D window looks like a straight line,
but in fact, these lines on the 2D version are not.
This is the advantage of 3D window.
We can guarantee that it looks like a straight line on the 3D costume.
Use the 3D version tool on the editing point and select the whole line once the 2D work is finished.
Press the Shift key to select the transition to the internal pattern.
When the 3D line is changed to the internal line,
you can manually modify the internal line
or directly select the internal line in the 2D window.
Next, I will continue to draw a cutout from the side. You can do it according to your own creative design.
When creating a shape, press the Ctrl key and click to draw a curve, just like in the 2D window.
To make it easier to cut out later, go to the outside of the board and press double-click to complete the creation.
Use the edit tool again to turn the line into an internal shape.
Then go to the 2D window and select this line, then press the right-click to select the cutout.
Next, you can continue to create your design according to your needs.
After cutting and sewing, remember to turn on the simulation and apply the changes.
After the design is complete, we will start adjusting the fabric.
Since we have a pin design, we will use at least two types of fabrics.
For fabric texture, we can go to the Substance file in the library window and get the material.
Find the Tracout material and drag it onto the swimsuit.
The texture of the swimsuit will be replaced by this material.
Go to the top right corner of the cloth window, you will see that the entire fabric texture has been replaced.
Next, we will create another fabric and place another material, go to the Fabric folder.
Change it to a grid diagram and then select any knit fabric.
Because most of these fabrics are elastic, they are suitable for swimsuits.
Here we choose the Cotton Jersey fabric.
We need to drag this fabric to the fabric window to add it to a fabric type.
Press the Shift key.
Press the Shift key to select all the fabrics that you want to use.
Then drag the new fabric to the selected sheet and apply this fabric to them.
Next, we will change the color of this fabric.
First, we select the Substance fabric in the fabric window.
In the user definition at the bottom, change the color.
Here I chose black.
The properties of the SBA-CR material can be adjusted in the property editor.
Just like in Substance.
Then select the Knit fabric and go to the color in the property editor to change the color.
You can change the texture texture and color according to your needs.
Here I chose red.
After adjusting the fabric texture and color,
I will reduce the particle diameter of all the sheets from 20 to 5
to get better fold details.
But here the details of the swimsuit look good.
We just need to reduce it to 15.
Open the simulation application to modify.
Now you can export the project in the software
and go to other 3D software for rendering.
Welcome to check out other summer atmosphere series tutorials
to learn how to make other content in this scene.
Thank you for watching.